It's one of the most popular and Powerful server Technologies today
Experts are among the highest paid in the industry allows you to build entire web software and
Only one programming language and it's time for you to understand it properly
Welcome to learn and understand nodejs
Hi
I'm Tony Alicia
My 15-year veteran of web application development and user experience design
And welcome to this course
In this course we're going to take a deep dive under the hood of nodejs
The famous
Popular server technology that lets us
Write server code in JavaScript
This course is not about
Diving into
Just
What nodejs is and what you can do with it
Discourse
Has to do with my fundamental philosophy when it comes
Learning
Especially when it comes to learning code
My Philosophy is this
Don't imitate
Understand
I think the biggest problem with most coding books and online tutorials and videos
Is that
The focus is on imitation
Another words
The instructor write some code
And then you write that code
And then the supposition is that oh
You know what you're doing
But then you get out into the real world and face problems that are different than the ones you see in the course
We Fall Down
Why
Because much more important than simply imitating someone else's code
Is understanding what that code is actually doing
So in this course we're not just going to see examples and we'll see plenty
We're going to
Focus
I'm truly understanding not just what the how and why
How does nodejs work
Why is it structured the way it is
How can I use the fundamental JavaScript knowledge that I need
And that you came through this course
In order to become a better know JS developer
For example this code here is where most node
JS courses start
And it's awesome it's
A web server in just a few lines of code of JavaScript code
Question is why you could install node
And run this code
And watch your web server start
Do you really understand what's happening
Under the hood
Do you understand what's happening
From a JavaScript perspective
All the elements and aspects of this code
That question
Is the one that will Define
Weather
You're imitating
Are you understanding
And so in this course again
We're not just going
To write code we're going to work on understanding what's really happening and why it's working the way
It is
So we're not ready for this code
We're going to take several steps back
And look
Under the hood to see
What's really happening and eventually
We'll get back here
But
Our primary intent
Is don't
Imitate understand
So will
Take
Again I'll look
Under the hood
Will dive into the V8 engine
The JavaScript engine that's at the core of nodejs
As well as
What nodejs is adding on
To that V8 engine
In order to expand the JavaScript language
And turn it into something that we can use
To write server code
And being a good nodejs developer means being an excellent JavaScript developer
So we won't just skim over JavaScript Concepts that may be unfamiliar
Emel examine that fundamental knowledge that you need
In order to understand
A particular area
For aspect or technique
Within nodejs itself
The better you know JavaScript
The better you'll be able to write code
Using nodejs
Alright
So don't imitate
Understand
And this course we're going to learn
And understand
Nodejs
Let's get started